Finding Aid for the Zoia Horn Papers LSC.2262
UCLA Library Special Collections
Zoia Horn papers
1934-2014
1935-2005
UCLA Library Special Collections
Marrion, Catherine
Horn, Zoia
LSC.2262
27.8 linear feet (56 document boxes, 8 shoeboxes, 2 cartons, 2 flat storage boxes, 1 oversize flat storage box)
This collection documents the activities, writings, and political opinions of Zoia Horn. Horn was a California-based librarian, administrator, and activist. She is best known for refusing to testify in the 1972 Harrisburg Seven trial, becoming the first librarian to be jailed for refusing to divulge information. Horn was also an outspoken opponent of censorship, government overreach, and discrimination. This collection spans from 1918 to 2014, and chronicles Horn's time in California, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey, and her work in the American Library Association.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Catherine Marion, 2014.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9977946683606533
Biography/History
Zoia Markova Polisar was born in Odessa, Ukraine on March 14, 1918 to a secular Jewish family. In 1926, her family immigrated to New York City. She attended Brooklyn College and the Pratt Institute School of Information and Library Science, first working in a library in 1942. She married Milton (Tony) Horn and had two children, Patricia and Catherine.
After leaving her first husband, Horn began working at the UCLA Library in 1965, where she became a tax-withholding opponent of the Vietnam War. In 1968, she was hired as Head of the Reference Department at Bucknell University in Lewisburg, Pennsylvania. In 1971, she moved back to California to work at the Modesto Public Library and married Dean Galloway, Director of Library Services at Stanislaus State College in Turlock, California.
In 1972, Horn was issued a grand jury subpoena to testify for the prosecution in the "Harrisburg Seven" conspiracy trial against Philip Berrigan back in Pennsylvania. Horn refused, arguing it would violate her professional principles of individual privacy and intellectual freedom. She served 20 days in the Dauphin County Jail in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. The American Library Association Executive Board refused to publicly support Horn's stand. It reversed its stance after the conspiracy trial fell apart. In 1974, Horn was elected to the ALA Council, and appointed to the ALA Intellectual Freedom Committee in 1977. She continued to work as an administrator at organizations like Right to Know and the National Committee Against Repressive Legislation, but never secured a job as a full-time librarian again.
After her release, Horn continued her campaign against censorship and government overreach. She was outspoken in her opposition to South Africa's apartheid and the racist ALA-produced film The Speaker (1977). She also protested the Patriot Act, particularly its sections on library surveillance. In 1991, she was awarded the James Madison Freedom of Information Award by the Society of Professional Journalists. In 1995, she published Zoia! Memoirs of Zoia Horn, Battler for People's Right to Know. In 2002, she was awarded the Robert B. Downs Intellectual Freedom Award and the Jackie Eubanks Memorial Award. In 2012, she was inducted into the California Library Hall of Fame.
Zoia Horn died on July 12, 2014 at her home in Oakland, CA at age 96. Since 2004, the Intellectual Freedom Committee of the California Library Association has awarded the Zoia Horn Intellectual Freedom Award each year, to honor "Californian people, groups, and organizations that have made significant contributions to intellectual freedom in California."
Scope and Content
This collection documents the activities, writings, and political opinions of Zoia Horn, a California-based librarian, administrator, and activist. She is best known for refusing to testify in the 1972 Harrisburg Seven trial, becoming the first librarian to be jailed for refusing to divulge information that violated her belief in intellectual freedom. The collection spans from 1918 to 2014, with the bulk of materials coming from 1935 to 2005. In addition to professional materials, including correspondence, press clippings, Horn's FBI file (obtained under the Freedom of Information Act), and unpublished manuscripts, the collection contains a large quantity of personal material, including letters to and from Horn, reflections on her time in jail, and interview recordings.
Some of the significant organizations and topics represented in these files are: the American Library Association; the Intellectual Freedom Committee; the California Library Association; the Coalition on Government Information; censorship; government overreach and surveillance; privacy rights; racism and sexism; and antiwar activism. The collection documents Horn's political radicalism; her time in jail; and her continued advocacy for marginalized groups in the US; as well as her opinions on education and democracy in America, her satirical wit, and her warm bond with family, colleagues, and friends.
Materials are largely textual, comprising correspondence, newspaper clippings publications, and related printed matter. Among other formats are photographs, negative, video cassettes, audio cassettes, microfilm, and ephemera.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Professional Records (1960-2005)
Series 2: Research and Writings (1960-2014)
Series 3: Personal Correspondence (1934-2014)
Series 4: Biographical Information (1943-2014)
Series 5: Books (1940-2013)
Series 6: Photographs and Media (1960-2014)
The collection's series have been kept in their original order following Zoia Horn's preliminary arrangement, and are organized by name or subject.
Marrion, Catherine
- Professional Records, 1960-2005
  Scope and Content
  Series is comprised primarily of letters, memos, resumes, and meeting minutes from Zoia Horn's career as a librarian and administrator. Materials span 1960-2005 and include documents from her work with the American Library Association, including the ALA Intellectual Freedom Committee; Horn's professional involvement in the Harrisburg Seven trial; and her activism within the ALA against South African Apartheid and the Patriot Act.
  Organization and Arrangement
  This series was set aside in a preliminary arrangement by Horn and has been kept in its original order. Folders have been organized alphabetically by name of employer.
  - American Library Association: Coalition on Government Information, 1985-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - American Library Association: Committee on Minority Concerns, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Library Association: Correspondence and Politics, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - American Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, Chicago Meeting, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, Rhode Island Workshop, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, South Africa Boycott, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, South Africa Critics, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Library Association: Library Bill of Rights, 1978-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Library Association: Loyalty Oaths, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Library Association: San Francisco Conference, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Library Association: South Africa, Association of American Publishers, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Library Association: South Africa, Chronology, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bucknell University, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - California Association of Library Trustees and Commissioners, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - California Library Association, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
  - Central Intelligence Agency Publishers, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dance Reviews, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Data Center, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Data Center, Right to Know, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
  - Freedom of Information Awards Dinner, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hay Fellowship, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Horn and Moon Biographies, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Job Hunting, Post-Harrisburg, 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Montclair Summit Plainfield, 1952-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Coalition Against Repressive Legislation, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey Library Association, 1956-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Racism and Sexism Awareness, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - Resume Documents, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Retirement, 2001-2014 (Box 5, Folder 1-4, Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - San Francisco Police Department Surveillance, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Speaker: Award, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Speaker: Bobker (Lee), 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Speaker: Braverman (Miriam), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Speaker: Broderick (Dorothy), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Speaker: Buck (Richard), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Speaker: Chronology, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Speaker: Eubanks (Jackie), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Speaker: Jones (Clara), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Speaker: Position, Anti-, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Speaker: Position, Pro-, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Speaker: Press, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Speaker: Resolutions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Speaker: Script and Discussion Guide, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Speaker: Zoia Letters, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stanislaus County Free Library, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Stockton Library, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Watchung Hills Regional High School, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Research and Writings, 1960-2014
  Series is comprised primarily of newspaper and magazine articles, newsletters, and online and written letters used by Zoia Horn for research purposes, as well as drafts, edited manuscripts, and reviews of her professional writing from 1960 to 2014. Materials include her research on censorship, government overreach, discrimination, and the future of libraries; her FBI file; and a scrapbook of articles on the Harrisburg Seven trial and her arrest. Materials also include her letters from jail after refusing to testify in the Harrisburg Seven trial; dance and book reviews; travel journals; and her memoir, Zoia! memoirs of Zoia Horn, battlers for the people's right to know (1995).
  This series was set aside in a preliminary arrangement by Horn and has been kept in its original order. Folders have been organized alphabetically by subject, based on original order.
  - Abortion Rights - African Americans, 1987-2011 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Aging - Alaska, 1987-2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ALA: Access and Information, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ALA: Conferences, 1977-2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - ALA: Confidentiality and Ethics, 1971-2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ALA: Foreign Relations, 1975-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ALA: Intellectual Freedom Committee, 1976-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ALA: Library Bill of Rights, 1965-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ALA: Membership, 1985-2005 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - ALA: Merritt Fund, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - ALA: United Nations Declaration, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Alzheimers - Art, 1998-2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bach Festival, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bagdikian (Ben), 1968-2008 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bagdikian (Ben), Press, 1970-2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Baker (Nicholson), 2000-2010 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven, 2000s (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Berea College, 1987-2009 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley City Club and Public Library, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Berman (Sandy), 1980-2004 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - Berrigan (Philip), 1983-2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bill of Rights at 200, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Black (Allison), 1992-2012 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Blake (Fay), 1967-2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Books, 1985-2011 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn College, 1939-2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Bryant (Dorothy), 2002-2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Bucknell University, 1967-2008 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bush (George): First Term, 2000-2004 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bush (George): Press, 2000-2004 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bush (George): Second Term and Impeachment Movement, 2004-2008 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - California, 2000s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - California Library Association: Fees, 1993-2006 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - California Library Association: Holocaust Issue, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - California Library Association: Intellectual Freedom Committee, 1971-2012 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Cameras, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Finance, 1996-2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Canada, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Capitalism, 1995-2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Censorship, 1971-2007 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Censorship: Ageism - Sexism, 1970-2010 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Censorship: Videos, 1988-1996 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Center for Investigative Reporting, 1977-2002 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1975-2007 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Central America, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Children, 1989-2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - China, 2000s (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Christianity - Church and State, 1991-2005 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Citizenship, 1974-2012 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Classism, 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Clinton Administration, 1994-2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Council on Interracial Books for Children, 1977-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Coalition on Right to Know - Coalition on Government Information, 1980-2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cold War Aftermath, 1996-2000 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Commercialism, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Computers, 1991-1997 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Personhood, 1989-2010 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Corporations (Enron), 1998-2008 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cuba, 1993-2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Current Events, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Data Center, 1973-2014 (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
  - Death Penalty, 1973-2009 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Democracy, 1975-2007 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Dissent, 1988-2007 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Downs Intellectual Freedom Award, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Drinnon (Richard), 1962-1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Drones, 2013 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Dying, 1987-2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1977-2007 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Engelko (Bob), 2002-2005 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Elections, 2000-2004 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Environment, 1995-2002 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Equality, 1975-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Eshelman (Bob), 1971-2004 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - Ethics, 1977-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Euthanasia, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Falling Prevention, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Dissent, 1978-2005 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: First Amendment Conference, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Horn File, 1970-1998 (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Libraries, 1983-2002 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: National Security Letter, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Politics, 1972-2005 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Fees, 1977-1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Fees: American Library Association, 1975-1996 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Fees: California Library Association, 1976-1997 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
  - Fees: Horn (Zoia), 1976-1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Fees: Press, 1977-1995 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Fenton (Tom), 1996-2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - First Amendment, 1977-1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1974-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Global Exchange, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Global Warming, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Globalization, 1996-2001 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Gorodnitzi (Sascha), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Government Intimidation, 1974-2006 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Guatemala - Guns, 1996-2012 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Harrisburg Seven, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Harrisburg Seven: American Library Association, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Harrisburg Seven: American Library Association, Intellectual Freedom Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Chenoweth (Gene), 1971-1977 (Box 15, Folder 15, Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Costs, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 4-9)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Dauphin Prison, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Galloway (Dean) Letters, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Government Intimidation, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Grand Jury Investigation, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Horn (Zoia), 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 7-9, Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Jail, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Legal Papers, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Harrisburg Seven: Statements of Support, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Hate Speech, 1989-2002 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Hay Fellowship, 1959-1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Holocaust Museum, 1980-1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Horrocks (Norman), 2002-2010 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Immigrants - Incomes, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Indexing, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Indigenous Peoples, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Information Censorship - Information Policy, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Intellectual Freedom, 1967-2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Intellectual Freedom Principles, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Intellectual Property - Iran, 1994-2007 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Iraq, 1998-2005 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Islam, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Israel, 1989-2009 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Israel: American Library Association, 1984-1992 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Israel: Anti-Semitism, 1993-2006 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Israel: Censorship, 1992-2002 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Jenks (George) - Jobs, 1986-2010 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Jones (Clara), 1982-2012 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Josey (E.J.), 1982-2000 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Journal of Information Ethics, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Judaism, 1970-2006 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Kahle (Brewster), 2008-2012 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Kaiser Permanente, 2005-2007 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Kazantsakis (Nikos) - Kin, 1970-2011 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Kister (Ken), 2006 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Kissinger (Henry), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - KPFA Radio, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Krug (Judy), 1976-1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Ku Klux Klan - Kunkel (Erika), 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Labor, 1989-2007 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Lacey Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Lacey Report, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Lacey Report: Commission on Freedom and Equality of Access to Information, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Lacey Report: Interim Report, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Lake Park, 2009-2011 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Language, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - League of Women Voters, 2001-2014 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Lee (Barb) - Lewisburg, 1972-2002 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Liberation Theology, 1980-1986 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Librarians, 1970-2005 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - Libraries, 1978-2010 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Libraries: Business, 1974-1984 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Libraries: Education, 1977-1999 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Libraries: Fees, 1977-1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Libraries: Public Technology, 1972-2005 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Libraries: September 11 Effects, 1988-2002 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Libraries: Service to Poor, 1990-2005 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Libraries: Technology, 1994-2003 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Libraries for the Future, 1993-1998 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Library Bill of Rights, 1967-2005 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Library Profession, 1973-1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Literacy, 1970-1983 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Lobbying, 1983-2001 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Lottery - Loyalty Oaths, 1974-1992 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - MacKenzie (Angus) - McFarland and Co., 1986-2000 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Media: Private Ownership, 1999-2006 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Medicare, 1982-2007 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Medical Care, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Medsger (Betty), 1979-2012 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Meiklejohn Library, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Merritt Program, 2006-2007 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Midnight Cowboy - Militarism, 1965-2005 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Miller (Elissa), 1983-2013 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Milton (John), 1993 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Mitford (Jessica), 1996 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Mobbs (Anne), 1996-2006 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Moon (Eric), 1977-1997 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Moore (Michael), 2002-2009 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Morgan (Julia), 2011-2012 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Moyers (Bill) - Museums, 2005-2012 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Music, 1990-2006 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Mynow (Mary), 2007 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Nader (Ralph), 2004 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - National Coalition Against Censorship, 1977-1981 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Native Americans - Nelson (Jack), 1972-1999 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Newcombe (Barbara) - Niebyl-Proctor, 1990-2004 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Power, 1978-2003 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Oakland: Education, 2000-2007 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Oakland: Government, 2001-2011 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Oakland: Mayors, 2005-2012 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Oakland: Occupy Movement, 2011-2012 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Oakland: Public Libraries, 1999-2008 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Oakland: Visit, 1991-2006 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Obituaries, 1999-2009 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Obscenity - Online Research, 1978-2003 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Odessa - Oil, 1990-2013 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Olver (Ruth), 1974-2001 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Paratransit, 2011-2013 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Pathways Breast Cancer Research, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Patriot Act: Homeland Security, 2002-2006 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Patriot Act: Libraries, 2002-2007 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Peattie (Noel), 1984-1989 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Pell (Eve), 1989-1998 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - People: Special, 1990-2008 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - People for the American Way - Physicists for Social Responsibility, 1981-2003 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Physical Therapy, 2003-2004 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Piano, 2003-2011 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Polisar (Barry), 1977-1997 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Political Correctness, 1990-1994 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Poverty, 1972-2006 (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
  - Prison, 1972-2005 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Prison: Library Services, 1970-1980 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Prison: Sawyer (John), 1970-2006 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Privacy, 1974-2011 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Privacy: Spying, 1974-2006 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Privitization, 1996-2001 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Program on Corporations, Law and Democracy, 2001-2006 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Propaganda - Publishing, 1996-2008 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Quotations, 1972-1991 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Racism, 1974-2009 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Racism: Reform, 1977-2005 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Racism: Shockley, 1972-1977 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Radio Frequency Identification, 2005-2006 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Religion, 1991-2005 (Box 27, Folder 7)